<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide Lucknow,India</string>
    <!-- Category name for hotels category [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_hotels">Hotels</string>

    <!-- Category name for Historical Monuments category [CHAR LIMIT=20] -->
    <string name="category_monuments">Historical Monuments</string>

    <!-- Category name for restaurants category -->
    <string name="category_restaurants">Restaurants</string>

    <!-- Category name for  shopping category -->
    <string name="category_shopping">Shopping Destinations</string>

    <!-- Category name for  category -->
    <string name="category_tourist_attractions">Other Tourist Attractions</string>
    <string name="Clarks">Clarks Avadh</string>
    <string name="clarks_description">Overlooking Lucknow city and the Gomti River, this upmarket business hotel is a 12-minute walk from Sikandar Bagh villa and 15 km from Chaudhary Charan Singh International Airport.\nHigh-end rooms and suites come with free Wi-Fi and flat-screen TVs, as well as minibars, and tea and coffeemaking facilities. Some have city, river and/or pool views. Room service is offered.\nBreakfast and parking are complimentary. A refined, top-floor restaurant offers panoramic views of the city and river.</string>
    <string name="lebua_Lucknow">lebua Lucknow</string>
    <string name="lebua_description">Set in a restored art deco property, this polished hotel is 3 km from Nawab Wajid Ali Shah Zoological Garden, 4 km from Chattar Manzil, an imposing former royal palace, and 14 km from Chaudhary Charan Singh International Airport.\nColourful, classic rooms offer terraces or courtyards, plus free Wi-Fi, flat-screen TVs and safes. They also include tea and coffeemakers. Suites add private patios and soaking tubs. Room service is offered.\n\nValet parking is free. There are 2 restaurants, including an Italian eatery offering al fresco dining. Other amenities include an elegant bar, a furnished courtyard and a garden, plus an outdoor pool and a gym.</string>
    <string name="Vivanta">Vivanta By Taj</string>
    <string name="vivanta_desc">Set 9 km from Bara Imambara, a grand Shia Muslim congregation hall, this genteel hotel sits on 10 hectares of gardens in a domed, Colonial-style building. It\'s also 3.7 km from Dilkusha Cabin railway station.\nThe elegant rooms offer Wi-Fi (fees may apply), flat-screen TVs, minibars, and tea and coffeemaking facilities. All provide pool or garden views. Upgraded rooms add rain showers. Suites add separate sitting areas, while upgraded suites have living rooms and dining areas. Room service is available 24 hours.\nBreakfast and parking are free, and there are 2 restaurants.</string>
    <string name="Renaissance">Renaissance</string>
    <string name="Renaissance_desc">In a sleek tower, this upscale hotel is an 8-minute walk from Ambedkar Memorial Park and 3 km from the Hazratganj shopping area.\nContemporary rooms feature flat-screens, Wi-Fi (fee) and minibars, plus city or park views, and tea and coffeemakers. Club level rooms provide access a lounge offering free drinks and appetizers; suites add living areas with sofas. Room service is available 24/7.\nParking is free. Other amenities include international and regional restaurants, plus a cafe, a business centre and a gym.</string>
    <string name="novotel">Novotel Lucknow</string>
    <string name="novotel_description">In an area with parks and medical facilities, this polished hotel is 6 minutes\' walk from Singapore Mall and 24 km from Chaudhary Charan Singh International Airport. \nWarm rooms provide complimentary Wi-Fi, flat-screens, minibars and sofabeds, plus tea and coffeemaking facilities. Some feature city views. Suites have living rooms. Room service is available 24/7. Kids (2 per room) stay at no charge with a parent.\nA breakfast buffet is free. An airy restaurant has a terrace with city views.</string>
    <string name="fairfield">Fairfield by Marriott</string>
    <string name="fairfield_description">Set in a lively commercial district and across the road from the Indira Gandhi Pratishthan convention centre, this informal hotel is 12 km from Lucknow Junction train station and 13 km from Bara Imambara, a grand 18th-century Shia Islam shrine and congregation hall.\nThe unfussy rooms feature Wi-Fi (fee), flat-screen TVs, safes, minibars, and tea and coffeemaking facilities. All have marble bathrooms and panoramic city views. Suites add separate living rooms. Cribs and 24/7 room service are available.\nParking is complimentary. </string>
    <string name="piccadily">The Piccadily</string>
    <string name="piccadily_description">Across the street from a shopping mall and 1.9 km from Manak Nagar Railway Station, this modern hotel is 4.2 km from Chaudhary Charan Singh International Airport and 9 km from the 18th-century Bara Imambara shrine.\nBright, individually decorated rooms feature wood floors, free Wi-Fi, satellite TV and minifridges. Upgraded rooms have sitting areas, as do suites, which add dining tables and complimentary bottles of wine.\nFreebies include breakfast and parking. Dining options consist of a restaurant, a coffee shop, a bar and a bakery. A spa offers beauty and massage treatments, as well as a sauna, a gym and an open-air pool.</string>

    <string name="Residency">Residency</string>
    <string name="Residency_description">The Residency, also called as the British Residency and Residency Complex, is a group of several buildings in a common precinct in the city of Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India. It served as the residence for the British Resident General who was a representative in the court of the Nawab. The Residency is located in the heart of the city, in the vicinity of other monuments like Shaheed Smarak, Tehri Kothi and High Court Building.\nIt was constructed during the rule of Nawab Saadat Ali Khan II, who was the fifth Nawab of the province of Awadh (British spelling Oudh). \nConstruction took place between 1780 and 1800 AD. Between 1 July 1857 and 17 November 1857 the Residency was subject to the Siege of Lucknow, part of the Indian Rebellion of 1857. The Residency now exists as ruins.\nThe Residency has been maintained as it was at the time of the final relief, and the shattered walls are still scarred by cannon shot. Even since Indian Independence, little has changed. \nThe ruined building is surrounded by lawns and flowerbeds and is a tourist attraction nowadays. \nThe cemetery at the nearby ruined church has the graves of 2000 men, women and children, including that of Sir Henry Montgomery Lawrence who died during the siege.The Ruins of the British Residency.\nThere is a weathered epitaph near the grave of Sir Henry that reads "Here lies the son of Empire who tried to do his duty" while another nearby grave reads "Do not weep my children, for I am not dead, but am sleeping here." A light and sound show to display the history of the Residency is also played each evening.</string>
    <string name="Rumi_Darwaza">Rumi Darwaza</string>
    <string name="Rumi_Darwaza_description">The Rumi Darwaza in Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India, is an imposing gateway which was built under the patronage of Nawab Asaf-Ud-daula in 1784.v It is an example of Awadhi architecture.The Rumi Darwaza, which stands sixty feet tall, was modeled (1784) after the Sublime Porte (Bab-iHümayun) in Istanbul.\nIt is adjacent to the Asafi Imambara in Lucknow and has become a logo for the city of Lucknow. It used to mark the entrance to Old Lucknow City, but as the City of Nawabs grew and expanded, it was later used as an entrance to a palace which was later demolished by the British insurgents.\nThis massive gate is situated between Bara Imambara and Chota Imambara. This place is generally very much busy all day, and during weekends most of the tourists visit. The streets are re developed as it was earlier constructed of hard brick roadways.</string>
    <string name="Satkhanda">Satkhanda</string>
    <string name="Satkhanda_description">The word \'Satkhanda\’ means Seven-Storeyed. Initially, this building was intended to comprise seven storeys but it\’s construction work was later abandoned and thus, only 4 level of it could be completed. Incomplete but nevertheless splendour of heritage architecture, Satkhnada, a red-brick watch-tower, constructed by King Mohammed Ali Shah, is situated near the Chota Imambara.\n Satkhanda, a four-storey tower, has got it\’s architectural design influenced from \‘The Leaning Tower of Pisa\’, one of the seven wonders of world. The tower is constructed in a blend of Greek and Islamic architecture.\n It\’s framework and pediments reflect Greek structural design whereas arches of the gates and windows show influence of Islamic structural design. The height of the octagonal ground floor of this structure is almost 10 feet, making it the highest storey of this tower. One of the distinctive feature of this structure is that each of it/’s successive storey has been constructed in the decreasing order of height and breadth of it\’s base storey. The total height of Satkhanda is 35 feet approximately. The tower has numerous triple-arched huge windows and compartments. A flight of spiral steps leads to the different storeys of the building. From the uppermost storey of the facade, one can see the beauty of the city\’s adjacent area.</string>
    <string name="Chattar_Manzil">Chattar Manzil</string>
    <string name="Chattar_Manzil_description">The Chattar Manzil or Umbrella Palace is a building in Lucknow in Uttar Pradesh which served as a palace for the rulers of Awadh and their wives.\nIt was constructed by order of Nawab Ghazi Uddin Haider and completed after his death by his successor, Nawab Nasir Uddin Haider.\nThe Chattar Manzil stand on the banks of the River Gomti. The Chattar Manzil consisted of a Bari (larger) Chattar Manzil and Chhoti (smaller) Chattar Manzil, however only the larger one still exists. These two buildings were examples of the Indo-European-Nawabi architectural style, even though the Bari Chattar Manzil has been altered over the years. The palaces were named after the chattris (umbrella-shaped domes) on the octagonal pavilions, which crown the buildings. The imposing building has large underground rooms and a dome surmounted by a gilt umbrella.</string>
    <string name="Safed_Baradari">Safed Baradari</string>
    <string name="Safed_Baradari_description">The Safed Baradari  is a white marbled building in Lucknow.\nIt was built by Nawab Wajid Ali Shah as a \'palace of mourning\' and was named Qasr-ul-Aza. Initial purpose of this building was to be used as an Imambara for observing \'azadaari\' (mourning) for the martyrdom of Imam Hussain and his followers at Karbala.\nAfter the annexation of Awadh in 1856, the Baradari was used by the British to hold court for petitions and claims by the officers and nobles of the deposed King\'s reign and his relatives. Later (around 1923) it was handed over, as a gesture of appreciation for their submission and loyalty to the Queen of the British Empire, to the Taluqadars of Awadh for their \'Anjuman\' (association) which was renamed as the British India Association of Oudh. The Baradari continues to be in their possession and control.\nThe main hall of the Baradari has two marble statues of the Maharajas, Man Singh and Digvijay Singh of Balrampur, the founders of the association. The statue of Sir Man Singh was carved by Farmer and Brindley of London, at a cost of ₤2 000, and was unveiled on 13 August 1902 by Sir James John Digges La Touche, Liueutenant-Governor of the United Provinces of Agra and Oudh.</string>
    <string name="Imambara">Bada Imambara</string>
    <string name="Imambara_description">Bara Imambara is an imambara complex in Lucknow, India, built by Asaf-ud-Daula, Nawab of Awadh, in 1784. It is also called the Asafi Imambara. Bara means big, and imambara is a sacred hall built for the purpose of Azadari. The Bara Imambara is among the grandest buildings of Lucknow.\n\nThe building also includes the large Asfi mosque, the bhul-bhulaiya (the labyrinth), and bowli, a step well with running water. Two imposing gateways lead to the main hall. It is said that there are 1024 ways to reach the terrace but only one to come back. It is an accidental architecture.\nConstruction of Bara Imambara was started in 1785, a year of a devastating famine, and one of [Asaf-ud-Daula]\'s objectives in embarking on this grandiose project was to provide employment for people in the region for almost a decade while the famine lasted. It is said that ordinary people used to work in the day building up the edifice, while noblemen and other elite worked at night to break down anything that was raised that day. It was a project that preceded a Keynesian like intervention for employment generation. Construction of the Imambara was completed in 1791. Estimated cost of building the Imambara ranges between half a million rupees to a million rupees. Even after completion, the Nawab used to spend between four and five hundred thousand rupees on its decoration annually.</string>

    <string name="Tundey_Kebab">Tunday Kebab</string>
    <string name="Tunday_description">This is the cleaner, more hospitable outlet of Lucknow\'s renowned, 100-year-old, impossible-to-find kebab shop in Chowk, where buffalo-beef kebabs go for ₹5! Here the prices are higher, but the boys put on quite a show streetside for to-go orders, while the proper restaurant behind dishes up scrumptious plates of mutton biryani, kebabs and tandoori chicken for throngs of carnivores.\nThe minced-mutton kebab (eat them with paratha) here is impossibly delicious and a spicy punch in the gut. Rickshaw riders know how to find this place. It\'s tucked away down a narrow street in the bustling Aminabad district.</string>
    <string name="Prakash_Kulfi">Prakash Kulfi</string>
    <string name="Prakash_description">A KULFI IS NOT AN ICE CREAM. A KULFI IS A KULFI.\nServing the tastiest Kulfis in Lucknow since 1956, Prakash Kulfi is the best place to be in, if you are a Kulfi lover. An upscale and world class experience in the premium Kulfi category, Prakash Kulfi offers an authentic atmosphere where customers can enjoy our rich-flavoured Kulfi.\nOne of the best Deserts Parlours in Lucknow, Prakash Kulfi brings a distinct and recognizable taste to each of the flavours on shelf.\nQuality is never an accident; it is the result of planning, teamwork, and a commitment to excellence. We, at Prakash Kulfi take pride in serving the highest quality Kulfis and aim to provide the best traditional Kulfis passed on over the generations.\nCome and Experience the conventional Indian taste of Faluda and Kulfi at the best rates.</string>
    <string name="Dastarkhwan">The Mughal\'s Dastarkhwan</string>
    <string name="Dastarkhwan_description">Lucknow Dastarkhwan is a reputed name when it comes to serving Awadhi Cuisines with style and perfection. Focused on providing hygienic and authentic royal recipes of lucknow which our chefs have mastered to perfection over years. Lucknow Dastarkhwan is looking forward to build a customer centric restaurant brand and promote awadhi and mughlai cusines in india and international locations as well.</string>
    <string name="Royal_cafe">Royal Cafe</string>
    <string name="Royal_cafe_description">It a multi-cuisine restaurant specializing in a variety of Indian, Mughlai, Chinese and continental dishes that instantly become a favourite of all those who try them out at our fabulous restaurant with delightful interiors. These dishes are prepared in our kitchens with all the ingredients carefully sourced from sustainable sources. Everything is prepared freshly by us so that you get the original taste which you will want to experience again and again.\n They host a wide range of events and parties so that we can make a place in people’s hearts and also so that we can create memories that can be cherished for years to come. Be it Marriage parties, Birthday bashes or year-end celebrations, we cater to the needs of all such events and also organize our own functions which are truly a memorable event for the city entire.</string>
    <string name="Moti_mahal">Moti Mahal Restaurant</string>
    <string name="Moti_mahal_description">If Mughlai meat country has got you down, seek refuge in this popular veg hideaway on MG Rd. It\'s perfect for breakfast (with great poori sabji – deep-fried bread rounds served with potato curry) or lunch. Come evening, head upstairs for more refined dining in the good-quality, low-lit, AC restaurant.\nYou could do worse here than try the Lucknow dum aloo (potatoes stuffed with nuts and paneer in a tomato-based sauce) and the kadhai paneer (paneer in a gravy made of capsicum, tomato, onion and traditional Indian spices) makes a stunning case for vegetarianism.</string>
    <string name="sharma_tea">Sharma Ji Ki Chai</string>
    <string name="sharma_tea_description">It is one of the oldest chai shop Lucknow city has got, it opens at sharp 5 am in the morning till late evening, Shrma ji himself sits in the tea shop and serves to its customers the one who lives outside the city surely visit the place when they return to city. Its a nice hangout place for the city, you can find many of the who of the who of the city in the morning time as well as any of the time, \nBun makkhan and circular samosa are also loved by the people of the city that this place offers.</string>

    <string name="hazratganz">Hazratganj Market</string>
    <string name="hazratganj_description">Hazratganj, the central shopping district of Lucknow, has a long history behind it and has undergone a great makeover that bridges the past and the present and continues to serve as Lucknow\'s central shopping arcade.\nIn 1827, the then Nawab Nasiruddin Haider laid the foundation of the Ganj market by introducing the China Bazaar and Kaptaan Bazaar which sold goods stuff from China, Japan and Belgium. The famous Taar Wali Kothi, Dargah of 12 Imam\'s at Khas Mukaam, Choti Chattar Manzil, Saawan-Bhadoh Mahal (the present location of zoo), the stunning Baradari, which was earlier situated between Kaiserbagh, Darulshafa, and Lalbagh also emerged during his regime.\nIn 1842, the name of the area was changed to Hazratganj after Nawab Amjad Ali Shah.</string>
    <string name="Lucknow_Zoo">Lucknow Zoo</string>
    <string name="zoo_description">Nawab Wazid Ali Shah Prani Udyan earlier known as Prince of Wales Zoological Gardens or popularly known as Lucknow Zoological Garden  is a 71.6-acre (29.0 ha) zoo located in the heart of the capital city of Uttar Pradesh. The Central Zoo Authority of India categorizes it as a large zoo. The Prince of Wales Zoological Gardens, was established in the year 1921 to commemorate the visit of His Royal Highness, the Prince of Wales to Lucknow. The idea of establishing Zoological gardens at Lucknow emanated from Sir Harcourt Butler, the Governor of the State.\nThe zoo is being managed as a trust by the Zoo Advisory Committee, with Forest Secretary to the Govt. of Uttar Pradesh as Chairman, Principal Chief Conservator of Forests, Uttar Pradesh as Vice Chairman and Chief Wildlife Warden, Uttar Pradesh as Administrator. An officer of the rank of Deputy Conservator of Forests is posted as Director for over all day-to-day management of the zoo.</string>
    <string name="ambedkar_park">Dr. Ambedkar Park</string>
    <string name="ambedkar_park_description">The Ambedkar Memorial Park was constructed by the Mayawati Government in Gomti Nagar, Lucknow. The park was built to commemorate the people who dedicated their life to equality and human justice like Dr. Bhimrao Ambedkar, Kanshi Ram and others. With a budget of a whopping seven billion rupees, the park is one of the loveliest things to see in Lucknow.</string>
    <string name="jmpark">Janeshwar Mishra Park</string>
    <string name="jmpark_description">Janeshwar Mishra Park is a newly constructed park, located in Gomti Nagar, Lucknow. The park is dedicated to a local namesake politician and is believed to be the 10th largest park in Asia. The park has a lush green atmosphere with a variety of plants and birds flocking the gardens. It comes under the green belt of Lucknow and is counted as a mini-forest.</string>
    <string name="math">Ramakrishna Math</string>
    <string name="math_description">Ramakrishna Math is a religious monastic order, considered part of the Hindu reform movements. It was set up by Ramakrishna pramhansa himself in Kolkata, India. The headquarters of Ramakrishna Math and its twin organisation, Ramakrishna Mission is at Belur Math (in West Bengal, India).\nAlthough Ramakrishna Math and Ramakrishna Mission are legally and financially separate, they are closely inter-related in several other ways and are to be regarded as twin organizations. All branch centres of Ramakrishna Math come under the administrative control of the Board of Trustees, whereas all branch centres of Ramakrishna Mission come under the administrative control of the Governing Body of Ramakrishna Mission.\n</string>
    <string name="Marine_Drive">Marine Drive</string>
    <string name="marine_drive_description">Marine Drive is named after the famous Marine Drive in Mumbai. It is a picturesque strip of road adjacent to the River Gomti in Gomti Nagar, Lucknow. The spot is popular among the young crowd as a hangout place. Apart from that, people use it for jogging, cycling and similar activities. The path is sprinkled with benches to sit and relax.</string>
</resources>
